I hate it soooo much.
If I don't answer, it won't start, right? Maybe.
Oh, no!
I thought Kameda-san was here, but today...
Hello?
Oh, hello?
Thank you for the other day.
What? Thank you for the other day?
I just wanted to thank you for that special call.
Yes, yes.
I made the call.
They were very happy to hear from you.
They were very happy. Hold on a second.
Thank you very much.
You know what I'm talking about.
It's so embarrassing to go and guess and get it wrong.
Can you tell us?
No, guess.
What?
Guess.
I'm sorry about the other day.
You left a long message, didn't you?
Why did everyone listen to me so attentively?
Thank you.
Message?
You even prepared a playlist.
You sent me a playlist, too.
What?
Because of that playlist.
I could listen to them in class.
Aaaaah!
You're Kou-sensei!
Yes, it's me, Hiburi.
Can you please stop making up your voice?
I'm not making it up.
Really?
Oh, I see.
No, I mean, you haven't, I mean, how long ago was that?
No, I mean since Corona started.
I see.
Yes.
Last year.
Oh, I thought it was something.
No, it's just that it's so real.
I mean, I've been to a few sites in the last couple of days.
And I just happened to make a playlist the other day.
Oh, I see.
Yeah.
Oh, but you don't...
Well...
I submitted the playlist to a certain program that I submitted the playlist to, and it was a radio show, and it was a radio show.
Oh, yeah, so I was thinking, there's no way you're a staff member of that radio show.
Mr. Rammacko, thank you very much.
I can't sing at all in class.
I told you that, didn't I?
In music class...
I don't know... what's this thing called learning to sing?
I forgot the theory... but it's all so boring...
Well, you know, it's just letters and notes
A long letter from Hama-kun and a song that says, "Please listen to this song.
I wrote a long letter from Hama and a song with a message saying please listen to the song.
Everyone listened to it with tears in their eyes.
I mean, you know, you even sent me an e-mail saying how it went.
Well, I was wondering how you liked it, but if that's the case, I'm glad.
I'll put the playlist up in the staff room.
But you know, you e-mailed me back then.
He said he didn't think you'd take it this seriously.
Yeah, you know, No Yalanine was amazing, because she wrote half a dozen texts.
I mean, if I went there and you and I had a little class or something, we could do it in spoken English, but with text, you know, I don't know.
I mean, if it was just you and me in a class or something, we could do it in spoken words, but in writing... and some of the kids might not know me, so there was a lot of writing.
I thought it would be better to do it in detail.
It was about seven B4 pages.
I don't remember writing that much.
I don't remember the details, but I do remember that I did it well.
I think I did the best job I could.
What are you in charge of now?
I'm still the student council advisor.
Oh, I see.
Yes, sir.
So you've changed Student Council advisor, right?
Well, you've changed since I graduated, right?
Yes, I was homeroom teacher once and now I'm Student Council advisor again.
You were homeroom teacher too? You graduated from us? That's how it works.
Well, you're still a musician.
I'm still a musician.
In Hama's day, everyone listened to music on their iPods, right?
Yes, they were already nose-shaped, you know, when they first came out.
People were talking about how many gigs of a good iPod they had.
Gigabytes, which is unimaginable now.
Why, you know, in that era...
Hama-kun was listening to a CD Walkman through it. I wanted to listen to it all the time.
But I think that's probably it. It's not like he used it all year round, right? Maybe they just didn't buy it.
What? No kidding?
Yeah, in that order.
You know, I kind of stupidly kept that thing with me all the way through graduation.
I had a dozen or so CDs with me at midnight.
Yeah, I know, I know. I know. They're like, in a case or something.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
You had them all in your hand.You had it in your hand, didn't you?
That's what I'm talking about.
Why did you have it?
You know... our generation...
When we entered junior high school...
The most popular type of gift for entering junior high school was an MD.
The most popular type of gift was the MD.
First of all, MDs were the most popular gift for junior high school students, too.
It was like a proof.
It was like a proof. Maybe that was true.
And then, everyone was buying and listening to MDs at the same time, and then, well, you know, Hiroki ruined it.
Hiroki was the one who ruined it. Hiroki and Katsutoshi. Hiroki and Katsura already had iPods when they were in the first grade of junior high school. I think it was the second generation or something.
Oh, that's it. I remember now. That's why that iPod is called
iPod
Because, you know, why, it has to read CDs.
There's no device that reads them.
You've been listening to a lot of music, though, haven't you?
Yeah, maybe that's why. CDs are faster.
Not because of the sound quality.
No, no, no, I don't think about the sound quality.
You don't think about it?
I'd take the CDs I'd bought to the general's house.
I'd take the CDs I'd bought to the general's house, and he'd import them and put them on his iPod.
I did that. I did that.
That's why people brought their own CDs.
I remember the new sale.
After school, I went out to the new sale.
I went to Tahara and bought the Tokyo Jiken album.
Then I came all the way back to Tsurukawa
Then I went back to Soukanchi and had them put it in Soukanchi
and back home with my iPod.
I already went back and forth, so I couldn't put it in at home.
It's already dark at home, isn't it?
So, the Sohkei's desktop already contains all the data of our great love of music...
Right... it has all the charts that are out of sync...
Yes, yes, it was in there.
You know, there was even a guy who started rapping.
There they are.
So there are demos from when they were students that they probably don't want to be shown anymore.
I'm sure there are some.
No, I'm sure they're there.
I'm sure there's some of Hama's practice stuff too... I'm sure there is... it was like a library, you know.
That's right. That's why they probably carried around CDs.
That's right. I miss it. It's not like that anymore.
That's right. We're in the age of data.
What are you going to do in the future, Okamoto?
Suddenly it's amazing, the theme.
Well, you know, thanks to you, two years have already passed,
It was our 10th anniversary.
So, if we can make it 10 years, it will be at the Budokan.
Budokan was not my goal, but it was a milestone.
I guess it is difficult to keep going...
I also realized how difficult it is to keep going.
What is the difference between Okamoto in high school and now?
I think they are completely different, in that sense. Of course, there are many things that have not changed,
I guess we have all grown up.
Is that all? Isn't that all?
Becoming adults? I don't know.
You become a better instrument.
Is that part of it?
A white Strat and a white Civan... all black... that's cool.
Is that so? That's old. It's a nice instrument.
What's that? The black shivan.
It's old.
It's the one they used for public recordings.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
It's a late Strat, very old.
It's really cool.
It's a 64 or something, right?
64. It's amazing, isn't it? It's all black.
Yes, it is.
Yes, there is that. But that's not what I meant...well, I guess you understand, but I was 19, so our debut was right after that. It was right after that. So, in short. So, in short, we graduated. So, when I look back on it, I can't help but feel like a student. For a few years.
I was fine, you know. You were fine, weren't you? Yes, yes. I think, looking back now, I can say that my attitude toward work was the same, and, you know, our conversations.
The conversations between the four of us, you know.
Yeah, yeah.
Like you were watching them after school?
I see.
So, you know, it hasn't disappeared at all,
But you feel that it's not good enough, right?
Yes, at some point.
When we were performing onstage, you know,
I was with, uh, Scandal Norina-chan.
Yes, yes. You know what I mean?
No, that's why.
Before I came in, so...
I did one. We did a doll on the Okamoto chart. Rina-chan was playing the drums, and she went on top of Okamoto's chart, right?
Yes, that's why Rina-chan came in halfway through. That's why you were in your second year. She was in her second year when we were in our third year.
That's why you came to Tokyo and entered our school,
I remember that she was the president of the student council, so when a new student came to the school, she would go to greet him or her. It was rare.
Yes, it was. Yes, there was.
When I went to Rina-chan's class, you know, we, the juniors and seniors, didn't get along with each other that much, right?
So all the juniors I know, you know...
They told me that the newcomer, Rina-chan, is going to MC next week, right?
I know, right?
And I told them that there's no way she's going to be there.
What are you talking about?
I told you, I told you, I told you, and you asked me what I thought about it, and I didn't know, so I gave you that information.
I don't know, so I'm just trying to get the information.
And I said, "What do you think?" And he said, "What do you think?" And I said, "What do you think?
Right? I mean, really...Right? I mean, really.
The next week, I was on M STAR, and I was playing Doll.
And the next week, I was listening to Yamato's performance, and Rina-chan was standing next to me.
Rina-chan was standing next to me and she was saying, "Wow, those girls are amazing!
I mean, how old was she, like 16, 17?
Rina-chan said that you guys are more powerful than Yamato Jim Skandar.
Well, yeah, but you see, that's the thing.
I was around, but not at Okamoto temple, right? I'm around, but not at Okamoto Temple, right?
I remember some things, but there are things I remember from talking to you.
I came to the Brahmin camp.
I went there after Gen's, Gen Hoshino's recording session.
Right?
Yeah, at Victor Studios.
Did you do it for me?
Hmm?
Did you? Did you talk about it?
No, I didn't, or I'd have made you feel like you were already in my head.
That's why I was late. I took the night bus.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. I picked you up at night, too. By car.
Right, right.
And I said, "I can't stay at the teacher's dormitory.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. Like you're a student.
Yeah, you're a student.
You're an adult now, aren't you?
No, you're right. You could've been someone else then.
I thought it was time to be a student.
I remember... that was the first night on the bus in my life... and it was by myself... and I was like...
That's right.
But you had already decided the day before.
He didn't say he didn't know if he could go or not, but he didn't know what time he'd be done recording, because you never know what time you're going to be done recording.
I couldn't say, "I want to go to my alma mater's camp, so I'm going home.
I can't say I'm going home because I have to go to my alma mater's training camp.
It was fun to go ahead and have breakfast with them.
Remember that? Before the students woke up.
The coaches would get to breakfast before the students got up.
And naturally, they'd be there waiting for them.
Town and Pee were all there.
I didn't even notice.
They were all egging me on.
As soon as I came in...
"Why are you here?
And I said I wasn't, but inside I was looking forward to it, right? That's right.
So we're eating, and he starts asking if itadakimasu, and no one notices me.
I started eating with low tension, like I'm the one who's going to say it.
Wait a minute, wait a minute, wait a minute.
Oh, there it is. You noticed? Did you notice that? That's a bit of a cacophony.
No, that was fun.
Speaking of outdoor stages...
Hama, I've heard from someone else that you and I were going to use the original house together.
Didn't you call Mr. Akko?
I didn't get it. I didn't buy any of my photos.
I'm sorry I didn't check the photos.
We played together on the stage.
Yeah, on the stage. We had some kind of Kouhaku Uta Gassen.
You weren't a big fugly then, were you?
That's right.
You were so ugly then.
You looked really shabby.
How much did you weigh?
But I'm guessing in the 60s.
Maybe 10 kilos, maybe a dozen kilos more than he weighs now.
So, when you say you're going to publish that book...
Yeah.
I mean, if you're going to put a lot of old photos in the book, it's going to be...
All the pictures are terrible.
So I'm the only decent one among them... I'm playing, so I'm looking down.
Oh, I see.
Yeah, that's part of it.
No, your vision was good.
It was like, the vision was good.
Oh, that's the thing. That's what I'm complimenting you on.
No, I mean, it's not an exaggeration to say that Mr. Acor's praise is one of the reasons why I'm here now.
Not at that time.
I'm really interested in everything, like radio.
I've been doing radio since I was 19.
Like I said before, I have words. I really do.
I don't know.
I don't know, I mean, I'm still in school, but... you know, it's an overstatement to say that I haven't changed since I was in school.
I should have done it.
Well, yes, I did. Mr. Akoh told me to be the MC.
We had a class music festival, freshman year, freshman year of high school, and we had a free time to put together an acoustic band with, what do you call it, friends and present.
Remember in the first year of high school, we had a class where we had to put together an acoustic band with our friends and present our performance?
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
Do you remember what we sang?
What was it, what did we sing?
They sang.
Of course, you were the host, but you were a better host than me.
No, of course not. I don't want to sing.
Oh, right.
Do you remember what you did? I don't know.
I was singing "Collabolue.
"Is he going to die? Or, "Is this guy going to die? I don't understand.
I don't get it.
It's like an acoustic band.
Who's going to accompany you?
I think they had someone from the construction crew come in.
Oh, I see. That's embarrassing.
Here's a clip of him singing with a microphone. Is he there?
I don't think so.I don't think I need it.
My head is shaggy.
It's a bit hairy, isn't it?
Yeah, I know. I don't remember singing.
I do remember that I was the emcee, though.
Hey. You're going to have to keep hosting.
I'll keep on hosting. I don't know if it's because of the hosting, or what.
I have a lot of respect for people who speak on the radio. I really respect people who speak on the radio. But there is one thing that I really admire. Of course, music is one thing, but after doing this for so long, there is one thing that I really want to do,
I do it with the feeling that it's my real job. Oh, really?
Please put more effort in that area as well. I understand. I'm glad to hear that. You were the first one to praise me.
I've heard all kinds of things...
I've heard all kinds of bad things about you.
Well, we're not science and engineering students, you know.
We're not students of science and technology. You know, you remember the case of the hidden cleaning kit case?
That was a boom for us.
That was a boom?
Yes, during the short break, during the 15-minute break or so, we would go into the cleaning tool boxes of different classes,
Then, when class started, they would stay in the box for about 10 minutes, and then, at a really random moment, they would open the box and leave without saying a word.
It really sucks, doesn't it? I think it really sucks.
Apologize to the cleaning toolbox.
It was always like that, you know. They all listened to the class with such a serious attitude.
I don't know if I should say this, but... Not everyone was polite.
But you did a lot of bad things.
It's not so much misbehavior, but it's not that bad.
It was just a prank, right?
Yes.
We would go to the new sales opener before Christmas and winter break and exchange gifts,
We all watched the show together.
We would do the exchange by the restrooms in the department store,
Who was it again? Was it me, was it me, was it me?
I bought about eight Harry Potter books off the shelf,
I'd buy about eight copies of Harry Potter off the shelf and give them away as a huge piece of luggage.
Rage was probably Warner Mycal Cinemas popcorn.
Rage got it?
The one Rage bought.
Rage is doing well, isn't he? I'm glad.
Rage is a parent.
That's right. He got such a beautiful wife.
Rage and Hama-kun had a baby with Dr. Mihosen's family when we were at the camp,
Oh, I miss it!
Remember?
What did we eat?
Sui-kun and Miita-kun. Wow, Sui-kun! It's been so long! Sui-kun! Rage was so cute, right? So was I.
Do you remember what we did? I don't remember what we did. He was cute. I remember we have a lot of pictures of him.
You guys don't remember the two of us talking shit all the time?
It's really disgusting. - No, I don't think so. I think it was Rage. We were doing it.
You're cute... but how old are you?
How old are you, Sui? Already a sophomore in high school. - Oh, my God, you're Sui-san.
Sui-kun? You can't say "Mr. Sui" anymore, can you?
I remember holding you and taking pictures with you, but...
No, I'm talking about you guys being naughty.
They say something like that. And when I see the footage of your debut, I'm pretty sure I'm that...
I'm a lot more excited than I thought I was.
Oh, you're so paranoid.
They're so excited.
I'm...
I'm surprised at myself.
That's probably why I'm trying so hard.
I'm just erasing it from my mind.
I wonder if the me that Akou-san saw was a little more intense than I remember.
I don't think so.
That's not true.
So maybe I was trying hard.
You were doing your best.
But when I hear you talk about it,
I don't think I did anything like that, but you did, didn't you?
Yes, I did.
That's bad, isn't it?
That's amazing.
I vaguely remember the locker joking around, though,
I'm sure that was part of it.
Understood.
Okay, okay.
No, but thank you.
What are your plans for the future?
Well, the band is going to be around for a really long time, that's the goal.
I'm going to the radio.
Yes, radio. I'm still doing it now.
Especially on AM. Come on AM.
Why not? Why not AM?
I like AM. It's kind of fancy after all.
Well, well, there's some kind of pathway. Then I'll do something like AM on FM, go for it.
Mm-hmm.
I'll do it while I'm wondering if you're listening.
I was actually listening the other day, coincidentally.
Oh, that's right. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
You don't mind if I message you, do you?
Sure, no problem.
Really?
You're gonna have to write it down, so, uh...
No, no, no, no. If you write that you've been teaching, you'll be chosen.
It's for this comic strip. Who? Send it to me in confidence.
Don't tell anyone. You'll be happy if I'm chosen, right?
That's right.
No, but you can do that anytime. And, I can't say I'll come visit you because of the situation,
But if you have a chance, please let me know.
I guess so. When you get settled, please come and meet my juniors.
Yes, I would. I don't really know the names of the teachers, but there are a lot of juniors I don't know, so please give them my best regards.
Yes, that's right.Yes, we are.
Because everyone is very happy.
I'll send you the book, as Akou-san sometimes says properly. It's got pictures in it.
Seriously? I'm so glad.
Please sign it.
Can I just send it to Mr. Akou at the school address in the staff room?
I've never had Hama-kun sign anything.
I'll write it down.
I'll drop you a line again.
Please contact me anytime.
Thank you for always returning my calls.
I'm not sure if you have that much time on your hands, but you really do. I know it sounds like I'm saying, "I don't have that much time on my hands," but you really do reply to my LINE messages right away.
I mean, it's normal for people to do that. But there are people who don't return messages at all.
Well, then, I was chosen.
That's right. I was chosen.
Thank you.
No, no, it's my pleasure.
Yes, sir.
Thank you very much.
I'm going to go have dinner.
Okay. See you later.
Okay. Good night.
Good night.
Okay.
I see.
Back up. Aim from the U-Kara.